Anthony Oliver

in anthonyoliver

xamox

About

I have worked in various areas of software development (full stack), including co-founding a venture-backed startup, obtaining a patent, and authoring a technical book. My experience spans from vision-guided robotics to GIS for the Michigan Department of Transportation. I've also collaborated with a Michigan Technological University professor and co-founded a company. I worked for Google as part of the Summer of Code program. I am committed to continuous learning in tech (LLMs, ML, Cloud, Security), maintain a homelab, and enjoy tinkering with tech projects in my spare time.

Highlights _____

- Startup Co-founder (Venture Backed Multiple Rounds): Sight Machine 🗹
- Patent #9955123: Machine-vision system and method for remote quality inspection of a product 🗹
- CKA: Certified Kubernetes Administrator
- Author of Computer Vision book on Oreily: Practical Computer Vision with SimpleCV
- Main contributor on open source project with thousands of users: SimpleCV
- Have worked in all major cloud venders (AWS, GCP, Azure, IBM)
- Helped Company obtain SOC2 Compliance

Education

BS Michigan Technological University - Software Engineering Sept 2001 - Dec 2006

Remote

Apr 2021 - present

3 years 5 months

- President local Association of Computing Machinery (ACM) Chapter
- Member of the Linux Users Group (LUG)
- Focus: Robotics and Manufacturing

Experience _____

HERE Technologies - Lead Devops Engineer

- Implemented DevOps best practices, streamlining deployment processes across cross-functional teams.
- Developed an automated deployment tool featuring testing, rollback, semantic version control, and release notes.
- Led cost reduction initiatives, optimizing team setups and reducing organizational
- Established and maintained DevOps and security standards organization-wide.

Sysdig - Senior Infrastructure Engineer

- Maintained AWS and IBM Cloud environments within the Cloud Infrastructure team.
- · Automated and supported Kubernetes clusters, managing underlying VMs, storage, and databases.
- Served as a Site Reliability Engineer (SRE), supporting thousands of customers on-
- Managed infrastructure for monitoring and supporting other companies systems.

Sight Machine - Co-Founder / Lead DevOps Engineer

• Scaled company from 2 to over 100 employees, developing software running 24/7 at Fortune 500 companies.

Remote Oct 2020 - Apr 2021 6 months

Ann Arbor, MI / Remote Apr 2011 - Oct 2020 9 years 6 months

- Managed Kubernetes (since v1.5) in AWS, GCP, and Azure production environments with advanced configurations.
- Achieved SOC2 compliance and executed seamless customer migrations across AWS, GCP, and Azure.
- Created in-house tools for development and deployment, and engineered fullstack solutions for edge device configuration.
- Supported legacy vision system customer with custom solutions during company transition to manufacturing analytics.
- Built a real-time vision inspection system for Chrysler, outperforming systems in 11 manufacturing plants.

Switchback - Web Developer

Ann Arbor, MI Nov 2010 – Apr 2011

5 months

CEC Controls - Vision System Engineer

Wixom, MI Apr 2008 – Oct 2010 2 years 6 months

Applied Manufacturing Technologies - Robotics Engineer

Wixom, MI Apr 2008 – Oct 2010 2 years 6 months

Google - Summer of Code Student

Remote June 2007 – Aug 2007 2 months

Volunteer _

A2Geeks Non-Profit

- Helped incorporate 501(c)3 non-profit for the benefit of the local community
- Helped organize and execute local events (makerfaire, ignite talks, etc

Google Summer of Code Mentor

• Helped students develop their skills and work on an open source project, went on to Facebook/Booking.com

Technologies

DevOps Tools: Kubernetes, Docker, CDK, Ansible, Chef, ArgoCD, Terraform, Elasticsearch, Kibana, Prometheus, Grafana, Kafka, RabbitMQ, Sentry, Sysdig, Helm, Helmfile, Fluentd, GitOps, Jenkins, StackStorm, CircleCI, TravisCI, PagerDuty, OpsGenie, Packer, Telepresence, Velero, JFrog, Harbor

Cloud Platforms: AWS, GCP, Azure, IBM Cloud, Digital Ocean

Backend / Platform: MongoDB, Cassandra, PostgreSQL, MySQL, Redis, Python, Flask, MVC, PHP, RESTful Services

Programming Languages: Python (Master), Java (Intermediate), JavaScript (Intermediate), PHP (Intermediate), C / C++ (Intermediate), Go (Beginner)